<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2022-01-25T14:30:58+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Orange AIVC</title><subtitle>AIVC is an end-to-end neural video codec,  offering performance competitive with HEVC.</subtitle><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><entry><title type="html">Description of a Pot Still</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2016/08/29/example-post-three/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Description of a Pot Still" /><published>2016-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2016/08/29/example-post-three</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2016/08/29/example-post-three/"><![CDATA[<p>A pot still is a type of still used in distilling spirits such as whisky or brandy. Heat is applied directly to the pot containing the wash (for whisky) or wine (for brandy). This is called a batch distillation (as opposed to a continuous distillation).</p>

<p>At standard atmospheric pressure, alcohol boils at 78 °C (172 °F), while water boils at 100 °C (212 °F). During distillation, the vapour contains more alcohol than the liquid. When the vapours are condensed, the resulting liquid contains a higher concentration of alcohol. In the pot still, the alcohol and water vapour combine with esters and flow from the still through the condensing coil. There they condense into the first distillation liquid, the so-called “low wines”. The low wines have a strength of about 25–35% alcohol by volume, and flow into a second still. It is then distilled a second time to produce the colourless spirit, collected at about 70% alcohol by volume. Colour is added through maturation in an oak aging barrel, and develops over time.</p>

<p>The modern pot still is a descendant of the alembic, an earlier distillation device.</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pot still is a type of still used in distilling spirits such as whisky or brandy. Heat is applied directly to the pot containing the wash (for whisky) or wine (for brandy).]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History of the Alembic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/history/external%20sources/2016/08/28/example-post-two/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of the Alembic" /><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/history/external%20sources/2016/08/28/example-post-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/history/external%20sources/2016/08/28/example-post-two/"><![CDATA[<p>Dioscorides’ ambix (described in his De materia medica) is a helmet-shaped lid for gathering condensed mercury. For Athenaeus (~ 225 C.E.) it is a bottle or flask. For later chemists it denotes various parts of crude distillation devices.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Alembic drawings appear in works of Cleopatra the Alchemist, Synesius, and Zosimos of Panopolis. There were alembics with two (dibikos) and three (tribikos) receivers.[4] According to Zosimos of Panopolis, the alembic was invented by Mary the Jewess.[5]</p>

<p>The anbik is described by Ibn al-Awwam in his Kitab al-Filaha (Book of Agriculture), where he explains how rose-water is distilled. Amongst others, it is mentioned in the Mafatih al-Ulum (Key of Sciences) of Khwarizmi and the Kitab al-Asrar (Book of Secrets) of Al-Razi. Some illustrations occur in the Latin translations of works which are attributed to Geber.[2]</p>

<p><em>Originally from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alembic">Alembic - Wikipedia</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="History" /><category term="External sources" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dioscorides’ ambix (described in his De materia medica) is a helmet-shaped lid for gathering condensed mercury. For Athenaeus (~ 225 C.E.) it is a bottle or flask. For later chemists it denotes various parts of crude distillation devices.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Description of an Alembic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/external%20sources/2016/08/27/example-post-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Description of an Alembic" /><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/external%20sources/2016/08/27/example-post-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/external%20sources/2016/08/27/example-post-one/"><![CDATA[<p>The complete distilling apparatus consists of three parts: the “cucurbit” (Arabic ḳarʿa, Greek βίκος), the still pot containing the liquid to be distilled, which is heated by a flame; the “head” or “cap” (Arabic anbiḳ, Greek ἄμβιξ) which fits over the mouth of the cucurbit to receive the vapors, with an attached downward-sloping “tube” (Greek σωλήν), leading to the “receiver” (Arabic ḳābila, Greek ἄγγος or φιάλη) container.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Retorts have the “cap” and the “cucurbit” made into one. The anbik is also called the raʾs (head) of the cucurbit. The liquid in the cucurbit is heated or boiled; the vapour rises into the anbik, where it cools by contact with the walls and condenses, running down the spout into the receiver. A modern descendant of the alembic is the pot still, used to produce distilled beverages.</p>

<p><em>Originally from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alembic">Alembic - Wikipedia</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="General" /><category term="External sources" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The complete distilling apparatus consists of three parts: the “cucurbit” (Arabic ḳarʿa, Greek βίκος), the still pot containing the liquid to be distilled, which is heated by a flame; the “head” or “cap” (Arabic anbiḳ, Greek ἄμβιξ) which fits over the mouth of the cucurbit to receive the vapors, with an attached downward-sloping “tube” (Greek σωλήν), leading to the “receiver” (Arabic ḳābila, Greek ἄγγος or φιάλη) container.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>